ALEXEY SITKO

Senior Data Scientist

SUMMARY

Full-stack data scientist & ex-consultant with 6 years experience helping businesses make the most of their data. I can help you make marketing more effective, understand customer behaviour, and find ways to make everyday operations run more efficiently.

EXPERIENCE

Freelance Data Scientist

03/2022 - Ongoing

Trego Analytics

London, UK

Freelance Data Science / Engineering / BI on a project-by-project basis.

- Setup A/B testing feedback loop for a next-best action CRM program for a Telco company in the UK, leading to identification of opportunity to reduce resource utilisation by c.50%.
- Developed a clickstream analytics and reporting BI solution for a charity organisation in the UK, leading to first view of website performance.
- Implemented performance reporting automation for scientific research publications for a Pharma company in the UK.

Manager, Data Science

01/2021 - 01/2022

Ekimetrics

London, UK

Responsible for the end-to-end design, build & deployment of data science solutions for clients in Retail, FMCG & Financial services. Managed teams of 2-6 data scientists/engineers in ETL, EDA, model training, testing & deployment.

- Developed a basket recommendation engine for a B2B chemicals business in 2 countries in APAC, which covered over 300 distinct products and included a monitoring dashboard in PowerBI to aid account managers with target tracking.
- Conducted regional **geo-lift test** for a B2B retail company in Brazil to measure the incremental value of digital marketing saving c.20% marketing budget.
- Built a cloud-based data mart for a global healthcare brand, which housed more than 50 marketing, financial, and operational data sources with a business-user interface, and fed marketing analytics models in 10+ markets globally.
- Carried out the discovery phase and POV design for a fraud detection engine for a B2B fuel card company in the UK in the transport industry.

Senior Data Scientist

07/2019 - 01/2021

Ekimetrics

London, UK

Team-lead on engineering, analytics, & insights work. Played a key role discovery phase activities (e.g. working with project stakeholders to define analytics and/or product requirements through design thinking). Project highlights:

- Developed a B2B customer segmentation and lifetime value (LTV/CLV) solution for an energy company in 9 EU markets, alongside a custom market-share tracking webapp/dashboard serving 50+ marketers and salesforce across the same markets.
- Conducted a group analytics project for a leading financial services company in 2 EU markets, to support marketing optimisation through marketing-mix-modelling, as well as campaign/creative planning through brand/sentiment analytics.
- Carried out a customer segmentation project for a transport company in the UK, leveraging unstructured third-party text data (unsupervised learning) which led to the identification of a +10-15% margin opportunity above the annual baseline through price restructuring.

Data Scientist

03/2018 - 07/2019

Ekimetrics

London, UK

- Conducted a project for a market-leading global CPG brand in the UK, that focused
 on price/promo optimisation and category modeling, resulting in the identification of
 a +40% headroom opportunity, including tactical pricing and distribution plan.
- Carried out model build for projects in Energy/Automotive brands in the UK and Russia, these included marketing-mix modeling and brand-lift studies which led to 10-30% better ROI on seasonal campaign execution in the following two years.

Data Analyst

09/2017 - 01/2018

ArcelorMittal

London, UK

INDUSTRY EXPERIENCE

Retail · FMCG/CPG · Financial Services ·

Energy · Charity

TOOLS & TECH

Core Tools

Python · SQL · AWS Cloud

NumPy · Pandas · sciPy · sklearn · spaCy ·

PySpark · MatplotLib · Seaborn · Plotly

Viz

Tableau · PowerBI · Streamlit

Cloud & Devops

AWS Athena · SageMaker · EC2 · S3 ·

Lambda · API Gateway · Glue · Cognito ·

Snowflake · Git · Gitlab · Heroku · Flask

CERTIFICATIONS

Certified Cloud Practitioner

Amazon Web Services (AWS)

EDUCATION

Imperial College London

Coursera Specilisation -Mathematics for Machine Learning

10/2022 - 01/2023

- Linear Algebra
- Multivariate Calculus
- PCA

London School of Economics (LSE)

M.Sc. Philosophy / Social Research Methods

08/2016 - 12/2017

- Causal Inference for Observational and Experimental Studies
- Regression Analysis
- Multivariate Analysis & Measurement
- Philosophy of the Social Sciences

Goldsmiths, University of London

B.A. Politics

09/2013 - 06/2016

· Analysis & reporting survey data